Guide to the Rice Television and Video Production records, 1999-2013 UA 406
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice Television and Video Production records
1999-2013
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 406
3 Linear Feet 3 boxes
These records include the creative output of the Rice Television and Video Production organization, which comprises student events and original programming.
Biographical / Historical
While the start date is unclear, Rice Broadcast Television [RBT] began original programming on October 29, 1998 with a topical news show focused on worldwide and Rice news stories. In that year, RBT received funding from the Vice President of Student Affairs office. In March 1999, RBT became a blanket tax student organization.
RBT continued in this way until April 2005 when it changed its name to Rice Television 5 [RTV5].
In Fall 2015, RTV5's leadership changed the club's name to Rice Video Productions [RVP]. Since they avoided going through the Student Association for this re-brand, they almost lost their funding access during a general election referendum. On January 23, 2017, RVP requested to no longer receive Blanket Tax Committee funding, because they considered that their mission included filming student events, but also original programming. The Student Association respected RVP's request and dissolved funding on January 30th.
RVP's YouTube shows that the group continued to upload content to the social media network, with the last group of videos uploaded on February 25, 2017.
Over its lifespan, the club mainly filmed events for other clubs and student events like Lunar New Year, Soul Night, and Beer Bike. It also dabbled at different times in original programming.
Content Description
These records include the creative output of the Rice Television and Video Production organization, which comprises student events and original programming. There are a variety of formats including DVDs, VHS, and digital videocassettes.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to the Woodson Research Center on 2017-06-28 by Kelley Callaway.
Index Terms
Subjects
Social life and customs; College students -- Texas; Universities and colleges
Document Types
videotapes
- Series I: CDs and DVDs, 2001-2012
  - Miscellaneous (1/2), 2001-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    These files are .wav, .avi, and .mpg on DVD. Disc titles include: "Windsync: First Half"; "Mixed Media"; "CBI Video Awards"; "VODS"; "Supershorts, Life on the Street, Runaway Bride, Small Room, KRM Pickle Shell World"; "Supershorts, Life on the Street, Runaway Bride, Small Room, KRM Pickle Shell World"; "POSADA"; "Battle o' Bands"; "KSDS Dances with Owls"; "President's Study Break"; "Greenscreen Time with Nico"; "Greenscreen: Leebron/Forman Get Rickrolled"
  - Miscellaneous (2/2), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    These files are unknown file types. Disc titles include: "Greenscreen Madness"; "Winds in Tights (1/2)"; "Winds in Tights (2/2)"; "Satin Hooks - KTRU Concert"; "Liberty Live"; "ENZO Spokesperson, Kyle Lee Music"; "Must play on DVD player"; "Richard, Luke (1/2)"; "Richard; Luke (2/2)"; "Mr. Plow Live"; "Price"
  - Shows and Programs (1/2), 2004-2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    These files are CD-R and DVD-R. Disc titles include: "Phil Final Movie"; "Run LOLA Run Parody"; "Top O' the Hour Episode 1: A New Hope"; "Ask an Athiest"; "Top Cocktail Live"; "Top Cocktail Live"; "Top Coffee"; "Norman Magic: Homecoming '08"; "Sugar and Spice Live Episode"; "Sugar and Spice Halloween Live"
  - Shows and Programs (2/2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    These files are CD-R and DVD+R. Disc titles include: "The Core (1/2)"; "The Core (2/2)"; "Ninja Episode 1"; "Ninja Preview"; "TOTS Season 1 Episode 3"; "TOTS Season 1 Episode 3"; "MKSAI Season 1 Episode 3"; "Jerry, Final Episdoes Disc 2"; "RTV5 Interview Series - Ping Sun"
  - SA Debates, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    These files are DVD+R. Disc titles include: "SA Debates"; "SA Presidential Debates"; "SA Debates"
  - Screw-Yer-Roommate, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    These files are .mp3 on CD-R. Disc titles include: "Screw Yer Roommate - Episodes 1,2"; "SYR - 2"; "SYR - 3"
  - Indie Rock Show, 2004-09 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    These files are unknown disc types. Content includes: "Indie Rock Show" discs from September, 2004.
  - 24 Hour Play, 2004-2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    These files are DVD+R. Disc titles include: "All files"; "All files"; "24 Hour Show (1/4)"; "24 Hour Show (2/4)"; "24 Hour Show - Sabine etc. (3/4)"; "24 Hour Show - Top Cocktail (4/4)"; "24 Hour Show"; "Ryan Berry"; "24 Hour Show"; "24 Hour Show Part 2"
  - Rice Rock Show (1/2), 2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    These files are unknown disc types. Content includes: "Rick Rock Show" discs from February through March, 2004.
  - Rice Rock Show (2/2), 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    These files are unknown disc types. Content includes: "Rick Rock Show" discs from March through April, 2004.
  - Ultimate, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    These files are DVD+R. Disc titles include: "Montage, Lunch"; "Montage Files, Powerball Files"; "Montage all files"
  - Backups, August 2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    These files are DVD+R. Contents include: "Backup" discs from August, 2005.
  - Forums and Talks, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    These files are CD-R and DVD+R. Disc titles include: "Diversity Forum Part 1"; "Diversity Forum Part 2"; "The Mathletes Interview"; "Mathletes and Others"; "Same Sex Marriage Advance Forum"; "Lindsay Interview"; "Clean Energy 1"; "Clean Energy 2"
  - Lunar New Year, 2004-2013 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    These files are DVD+R. Disc titles include: "CSA 1"; "CSA 2"; "Disc 1"; "Disc 2"; "Part 1"; "Lunar New Year Show"
  - Sports Tour (1/2), 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    These files are DVD+R. Content includes: "Baseball Alumni Game"; "Sports Tour" discs from 2004 to 2007.
  - Sports Tour (2/2), 2008 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    These files are DVD+R. Content includes: "Sports Tour" discs from January through October, 2008.
  - Spin Cycle (1/2), 2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    These files are of unknown disc type. Content includes: "Spin Cycle" discs from September through October, 2004.
  - Spin Cycle (2/2), 2005-2010 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    These files are CD-R and DVD-R. Content includes "Spin Cycle" discs from 2005-2010.
  - Soul Night, 2004-2008 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    These files are DVD-R. Disc titles include: "BSA Soul Night: Preshow"; "Soul Night"; "Soul Night (1/2)"; "Soul Night (2/2)"; "Soul Night (1/2)"; "Soul Night (2/2)"; "Soul Night: Extra Videos"; "Soul Night"
  - Beer Bike, 2004-2011 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    These files are DVD-R. Disc titles include: "Beer Bike Race: ENRON Tape (1/2)"; "Beer Bike Race: ENRON Tape (2/2)"; Beer Debates (2007)";"Beer Debates (2008)"; "Beer Debates (2011)"
  - O-Week, 2004-2008 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    These files are CD-R and DVD-R. Disc titles include: "Move-In (1/2)"; "Move-In (2/2)"; "Cheers, Jello, Lovett, Sid (1/2)";"Cheers, Jello, Lovett, Sid (2/2)"; "O-Week"; "Green Screen Madness"; "Leebron's BBQ"
  - Backups, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    These files are CD-R and DVD-R. Disc titles include: "SOS Disc 1 (1/6)"; "SOS Disc 7 (6/6)"; "SOS Disc 2 (2/6)";"SOS Disc 3 (3/6)"; "SOS Disc 4 (4/6)"; "SOS Disc 5 (5/6)"; "VoD"; "DVCam Tapes: Applesauce, Beinut, Miracle of Birth, Wendy's Challenge, WRC/Baker Freshman Flag"; "Mia Haman Shoutout"
  - Editors and Compilations, 2001-2004 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    These files are CD-R and DVD-R. Disc titles include: "RBT Disc 2 of 8 (1/2)"; "RBT Disc 7 of 8 (2/2)"; "RBT Track Lists"; "Jessica, Darius, Beyond the Hedges, Beer Bike 2001"; "Thomas, Richard, On Demand, News"; "Scott; Beer Bike Tape 1+3; Don't Delete (1/2)"; "Scott; Beer Bike Tape 1+3; Don't Delete (2/2)"; "Scott, Beer Bike Tape 2, Halloween Hoops, Football"; "Run Phil Run, Katie"; "Fall preview, Drinking with Phil"
  - Residential College-Related Material, 2004-2012 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    These files are CD-R and DVD-R. Content includes: "Wiess Jazz Nite"; "Mr. Will Rice"; "Edgar Odell Lovett College"; "Baker 13"; "Jones College-Hair"; "Mr. Rice"
  - 2 Graham Celeb; 3 Players Celeb; Beer Bike Parade; Rice McNeese State Volleyball; Rice SFAVB; Scott Beer Bike Parade '03 Final, 2003 (Box 1)
  - 927 Show Edit; Cheese Contest; Recruit Show Part 1; Recruit Show Part 2, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Baseball National Championship Celebration Part 1, n.d. (Box 1)
  - First Annual Jones Roommate Gameshow, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Hello Hamlet (3 DVDs), 2008 (Box 1)
  - RBT, Spring 2005 (Box 1)
  - Rice Philharmonics Hanszen Concert, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Rice Rock Show, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Rice Rock Show 1-24, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Rice Rock Show 2, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Rice Rock Show 4, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Rice University on Film, 2004 (Box 1)
  - PS Part 1; advanceclip; Rice Duke FB; Rice Houston VB; Rice Texas State, 2003 (Box 1)
  - PS Part 2; Basketball 1; Power Hour Commercial; Rice SJSFB; Slam Dunk, 2003 (Box 1)
  - PS Part 3; Rice Fresno State FB; Rice LA Tech FB '03; Rice SMU FB '03, 2003 (Box 1)
  - PS Part 4, 2003 (Box 1)
- Series II: Digital Videocassettes, 2003-2011
  - Halloween Hoops, 2003-10-31 (Box 2)
  - RBT 1 - Slam Dunk Original Footage, 2003-10-31 (Box 2)
  - Student Associations Presidential Debates, 2004-02-09 (Box 2)
  - Ellipsis Live "Don't Speed", 2004-08-28 (Box 2)
  - Ellipsis Live, 2004-08-28 (Box 2)
  - WBB Tulsa, 2004-10-17 (Box 2)
  - Dr. Lindsay, 2007-10-29 (Box 2)
  - Rice Sketch Comedy, 2007-12-01 (Box 2)
  - Chewston: x 3; Tea Trike AC, 2007-12-01 (Box 2)
  - Homecoming, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Homecoming Gala (1/2), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Homecoming Gala (2/2), 2008 (Box 2)
  - Sugar and Spice Season 1 Episode 3, 2009-01-16 (Box 2)
  - Battle of the Bands, 2009 (Box 2)
  - Servery Samurai, 2010-02-19 (Box 2)
  - Servery Samurai Big Cam, 2010-02-19 (Box 2)
  - Matriculation Speech, 2010 (Box 2)
  - Matriculation Sallyport; Hamlet, 2010 (Box 2)
  - My First Time, 2010 (Box 2)
  - SAS Show (2 tapes), 2010 (Box 2)
  - Rangeela T1, 2011 (Box 2)
  - Rangeela T2, 2011 (Box 2)
  - Rock the Vote "Tomorrow's Past", 09-24 (Box 2)
  - Top Cocktail, 10-15 (Box 2)
  - Golden Owls, 11-07 (Box 2)
  - Bakershake: Hamlet 2nd Time #1 (Box 2)
  - Bakershake: Hamlet 2nd Time #2 (Box 2)
  - Connor O'Hoolihan 3; O-Week South T and C (Box 2)
  - Elinn Screw Date Tape 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Eric, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Hamlet, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Jones Commons, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Left Close (1/2), n.d. (Box 2)
  - Left Close (2/2), n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mark's Lecture, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mr. Rice 5 Cam 2, n.d. (Box 2)
  - PICNIC The Nationals, n.d. (Box 2)
  - RBT 4 (2 tapes), n.d. (Box 2)
  - RBT 5, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Sid/Will Rice Powderpuff, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Strapped 4 Life Concer, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Sugar and Spice Season 3 Episode 1 (Box 2)
  - Untitled (2 tapes), n.d. (Box 2)
- Series III: Mini Digital Videocassettes, 2003-2013
  - Dr. Howell, 2003-02-16 (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 2003-02-21 (Box 2)
  - Richard, 2003-03-18 (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 2003-04-02 (Box 2)
  - Baseball Celebrations, 2003-06 (Box 2)
  - Baseball, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Beer Bike, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Beer Bike Parade - RBTI A, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Halloween Hoops, 2003 (Box 2)
  - RBT2 A, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Women's Basketball, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Women's Basketball/Men's, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 2004-04-29 (Box 2)
  - Beer Bike - Final Tape, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Sid/Wiess O-week, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Spring Collegiates - Tape 1, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Spring Collegiates - Tape 2, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Willy Week, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Rice O-week, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Beer Bike Balloons, 2005 (Box 2)
  - GSL Hurricane, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Beer Bike (2 tapes), 2006 (Box 2)
  - Interview, 2007-02 (Box 2)
  - Rice Sketch Comedy (2 tapes), 2007-12-01 (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Rice Small Jazz, 2008-04 (Box 2)
  - Hello, Hamlet! Act 1 - Cam 3 DKCam DVDUB, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Rally, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Sid Milk Chug, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Sugar and Spice s1 e3, 2009-01-16 (Box 2)
  - Servery Samurai (2 tapes), 2010-02-19 (Box 2)
  - Windsync Left, 2010-12-05 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting - Camera A, 2012-10-22 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting - Camera B, 2012-10-22 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting (2 tapes), 2012-10-24 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting (2 tapes), 2012-11-12 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting Steady, 2012-11-19 (Box 2)
  - SA Steady, 2012-11-19 (Box 2)
  - SA Zoom, 2012-11-19 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting, 2012-11-26 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting Wide 1, 2012-11-26 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting Zoom 1, 2012-11-26 (Box 2)
  - SA Meeting Zoom 2, 2012-11-26 (Box 2)
  - SA Wide 2, 2012-11-26 (Box 2)
  - Centennial Town Hall - Detail Shot, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Centennial Town Hall - Wide Shot, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Dean Hutch, 2012 (Box 2)
  - KTRU Outdoor Show (3 tapes), 2012 (Box 2)
  - KTRU Outdoor Show 1, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Soul Nite Pt. 1, 2012 (Box 2)
  - O-Week Leebs (2 tapes), 2013 (Box 2)
  - West Side Middle, 02-02 (Box 2)
  - SA, 02-11 (Box 2)
  - SA - Close, 02-11 (Box 2)
  - SA (2 tapes), 02-18 (Box 2)
  - Barr or Episode 4 - Connor, 02-19 (Box 2)
  - Servery Samurai, 02-19 (Box 2)
  - Teach-In A, 03-27 (Box 2)
  - Teach-In B, 03-27 (Box 2)
  - CWS on Fidd, 06-03 (Box 2)
  - UT Football, 09-21 (Box 2)
  - Poetry Slam, 11-20 (Box 2)
  - Advance, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Archie, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Ardice Speaker or Homecoming Gala - Small Cam 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Baseball, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Blackie, n.d. (Box 2)
  - BMG Films, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Brand (Box 2)
  - Buxton, n.d. (Box 2)
  - CEVE v. Physics Dogeball, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Chewston: 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Chewston 1 Mi Luna Primary, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Chewston: 3 Monday (Box 2)
  - Chewston: D'Amicos Primary (Box 2)
  - Chewston: Mono 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Cloud Nothing, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Cooking with Jack; 24-Hour play, n.d. (Box 2)
  - CRIBS Pilot, n.d. (Box 2)
  - David and Dean Show (Box 2)
  - Delicate Steve, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Disney Random Cellophane: Tape 1 (Box 2)
  - Dr. Lindsay (Box 2)
  - End Conference; Disney World (Box 2)
  - Feather FC, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Feather FC, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Interview Zach, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Joe McDowell, n.d. (Box 2)
  - LNY P1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - LNY P2, n.d. (Box 2)
  - LNY P3, n.d. (Box 2)
  - LNY P1 XXX, n.d. (Box 2)
  - LNY P2 XXX, n.d. (Box 2)
  - LNY P3 XXX, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Meg and Maggie A (Box 2)
  - Mental Health Rally, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mental Health Rally 3, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mr. Rice: CAM 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mr. Rice: CAM 2, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mr. Rice: CAM 3, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mr. Rice: CAM 4, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mr. Rice: CAM 6, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mr. Rice: CAM 7, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Nebula; R.W. Interview, n.d. (Box 2)
  - O-Week Rock Climbing, n.d. (Box 2)
  - O-Week Sun-Thurs AM, n.d. (Box 2)
  - O-Week Tape 2; Baseball Carnival 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Painting a Picture, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Peace Rally, n.d. (Box 2)
  - PICNIC The Nationals, n.d. (Box 2)
  - PICNIC The Nationals, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Pinafore 2, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Power Hour, n.d. (Box 2)
  - RBT C, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Richard 1 - RMA 1 Silhouette Footage, n.d. (Box 2)
  - RIS; Lovett Plays; Chocobar, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Robin - Tape 2, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Roommate Show Tape 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Roommate Show Tape 3, n.d. (Box 2)
  - SA 1 - I 28, n.d. (Box 2)
  - SA 1 - I 28, n.d. (Box 2)
  - SA MTN 318, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Scott, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Season 1 Episode 1 Forum - CAM 1 s4r, n.d. (Box 2)
  - SMOK JACKT Cam 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - SMOK JACKT Cam 2, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Stations, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Sugar and Spice: season 3 episode 1 (Box 2)
  - SWMP CBG FTHRFC P1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Talk of the Stations #1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Thursday Beer Debate; SA Changeover, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Two Guys w/ Guitars, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Wellness Debate 1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Wellness Debate 2, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Wellness Debate 3, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Wellness Debate 4, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Wellness Rally, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Wiess Tabletop, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Willy Week Beer Pong, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Women's Pro Soccer Mia Hamm, n.d. (Box 2)
  - WSS Wide (1/3), n.d. (Box 2)
  - WSS Wide (2/3), n.d. (Box 2)
- Series IV: VHS, 1999-2004
  - Owls Weekend, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Owls at Relicent, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Rice FB v. SMU Highlights, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Rice v. Hawaii Highlights, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Robin and Voting; Scott, Women, indecipherable, 2002 (Box 3)
  - SA President Turnover, 2002 (Box 3)
  - IM Games Highlights for Banquet, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Poetry Slam at Willy's Pub, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Rice v. Duke Highlights, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Rice v. SMU Fox Sports, 2003 (Box 3)
  - WCUB Champ/ MISC Champ, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Rice Rock Show Vol. 4, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Pinback, 02-24 (Box 3)
  - Travis and Gavin, 03-20 (Box 3)
  - 24 Hour Show Tape 13, n.d. (Box 3)
  - FB Hawaii, n.d. (Box 3)
  - IM Coed; Women's Basketball, n.d. (Box 3)
  - LA Tech - Scott Ellis, n.d. (Box 3)
  - RBT Owl Weekend Video (Box 3)
  - Rice v. Boise State; Olympic Torch Footage, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Rice v. Fresno/Tulsa Highlights, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Rice v. Hawaii Highlights, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Rice v. SMU Volleyball, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Rice v. UTEP Highlghts, n.d. (Box 3)
  - SMU/UTEP/LA Tech Highlights, n.d. (Box 3)